(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)
あの子を神として覚醒させます｡➡
I will awaken the child into godhood.
儀式の準備を急ぎなさい｡
Prepare the ritual at once.
I was once saved by your mother and your power.
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)私は以前 お前の母と
お前の力に命を救われたんだ｡➡
命に代えても
お前の母を助け出す｡
I will save your mother, no matter the cost.
それを忘れないでくれ｡
I ask that you do not forget that.
I am going to leave this place.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)私は ここから出る｡➡
I wish to leave here and meet this child, Mugaro.
ここを出て
ムガロという子に会いたい｡
You want to meet Mugaro?
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)ムガロちゃんに？
会って確かめたいことがある｡➡
I need to meet Mugaro and see something for myself.
だから 協力してくれ｡
So please help me.
7 Years Ago
Look!
It's Lady Jeanne D'Arc!
((ジャンヌ･ダルク様だ))
Drive back the demon!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((悪魔を打ち払え！➡
神のご加護は我にあり！))
The gods are our protectors!
Rage of Bahamut
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((お前たちは向こうを頼む))
(兵士たち)((はっ！))
I want your men to cover that side.
-We are tending to the injured villagers.
-Thank you.
(少女)((ジャンヌ様))
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((ん？))
Lady Jeanne.
Also begin tearing down
the damaged buildings.
((ありがとう))
Thank you!
What beautiful flowers.
((きれいな花だな｡ ありがとう))
Thank you.
((ふふっ))
Run!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((逃げろ！))
((ドゴッ！))
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)((団長！))
((ううっ… うぅ…))
Captain!
((はっ！ はぁ はぁ はぁ…))
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
((いけません 急に動いては))
No. You must rest.
What happened to the demon?
Felled by Dias and myself.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
((私とディアスで しとめました))
I see.
((そうか｡ はっ！ あの子供は？))
What of the child?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)((申し訳ございません))
I am terribly sorry.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)
((お前が謝ることではない｡➡
You have nothing to apologize for.
私が救えなかったのだ))
It was I who failed to save her.
(兵士たち)((てやっ！ せやっ！))
((キン！))
((≫(兵士)納得できんなぁ))
It's just not right.
((俺には あの人が ｵﾙﾚｱﾝの団長に
ふさわしいとは とても思えない))
She's not fit to be the captain
of the Orleans Knights.
((手負いの悪魔一匹からも
民を守れない))
Couldn't even save a citizen from a wounded demon.
((そのような人が団長であるなど
納得できん))
I can't accept someone like that as our captain.
((まあ そんなに腐るなよ｡
どうせ 上が決めたことだ))
Look, there's no use getting upset about it.
It's what the higher-ups decided.
((俺たちには どうにもできんよ))
((だが…))
There's nothing we can do.
-But--
-The higher-ups like her.
(兵士)
((上のお気に入りなんだろうよ➡
They want a pretty female captain.
美人の女団長さんはよぉ))
(兵士)((ちっ そういうことか))
I guess that's just the way it is.
(兵士)
((うわっ！ おおっ ふっ！))
(兵士)((ふっ！ ふんっ！))
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((あっ！))
Enough!
((くっ まだだ｡ うっ…))
Not yet!
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)
((ご無理をなさってはいけません))
You mustn't push yourself!
My apologies, Captain.
(兵士)((失礼しました 団長))
(２人)((あっ))
(兵士)((加減を誤りました))
I misjudged my strength.
((ふっ))
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)((次は 俺が相手だ))
You shall face me next.
((えっ？ ははっ…))
((キン！ キン キン！))
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)((せやっ！ てやっ！))
(兵士)((うわっ！))
Three years ago,
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((３年前 私は神を殺し➡
after I killed gods,
聖女としての力を失った))
I lost the holy powers I was granted.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((たとえ
この命を絶ったとしても➡
It is a sin I could never be forgiven for,
even if I were to pay with my life.
償いきれる罪ではないだろう))
((ジャンヌ様…))
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((私は➡
Lady Jeanne.
Even so,
I plan to continue to live my life as a knight.
それでも 騎士として
生き続けようと思っている｡➡
過去の罪 救えなかった命
無力である自分自身➡
My past sins, the lives I was unable to save,
my own powerless self...
それらを 全て背負って))
These are the burdens I carry with me.
((逃げることは たやすい｡
だが まだ諦めたくはない｡➡
Running away would be simple.
But I do not wish to give up yet.
Until I am stripped of my duties as captain,
いずれ 団長の任を解かれる
その日まで 私は➡
I wish to devote my life to the Orleans Knights
as your captain.
オルレアンの団長であることに
この身をささげたい))
((私たちは
あなたに ついていきます))
We will follow you.
Thank you.
((ありがとう))
((≫(重臣)まさか 本当に
神なしで即位されるおつもりか？))
Does he really mean to take the throne without the gods?
((≪(重臣)前代未聞だ｡
そんなことが まかり通るのか))
This is unheard of!
Can he really get away with this?
I am the new king of Anatae,
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)
((余が新たなアナティ王➡
Charioce XVII!
シャリオス１７世だ))
((そして このときより
人が魔を恐れ 神を崇める時代の➡
And acting immediately,
I declare that the days when men feared the
demons and bowed down to the gods are over.
終焉を宣言する))
I pledge to make a new world for mankind.
((真に人のための世を
つくり出すことを➡
You have my vow.
ここに約束する))
おお～～～！))
Your Highness, please reconsider.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((陛下
どうか お考え直しください！➡
Why are you attacking the sacred temples of the gods?
なぜ 神々の神殿に
攻め入るのですか？))
((それが
人の世のためとなるからだ))
Because it will lead to the betterment of mankind.
((必ずな))
((分かりません))
I assure you.
I do not understand.
Mankind and the gods have had
a long-standing connection.
((長きにわたる 人と神の関係➡
I simply cannot understand why you would
sever ties in this manner.
それを このような形で断つなど
理解しかねます))
There is something I must obtain.
((手に入れなければ
ならぬものがある))
But the gods refused me.
((しかし 神は それを拒否した｡
ならば 奪うしかない))
So I have no choice but to take it.
What is this that you seek?
((その｢もの｣とは？))
((余に従うなら教えてやる))
I shall tell you if you vow your allegiance to me.
((この国には お前のように➡
In this kingdom,
there are still those like you
who would worship the gods.
いまだ
神を崇拝する輩が存在している))
But if you, a former saint,
were to abide by my rule,
((だが 元聖女であるお前が
私の命に従えば➡
いいかげん
ヤツらも諦めるだろう))
they would surely give in finally.
So choose, Jeanne D'Arc.
((選べ ジャンヌ･ダルク))
Will you follow me and create a world for mankind,
((余に従い
共に人の世をつくり上げるか➡
この城を去るか))
or will you leave this castle?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((すまない 後は頼む｡➡
I am sorry. I leave the rest to you.
Rage of Bahamut
バタン！
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((はっ))
((選べ ジャンヌ･ダルク))
Choose, Jeanne D'Arc.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((ミカエル様…｡➡
Lord Michael.
うぅ…))
((はっ))
((うっ！ うわぁ～！ ああっ！➡
はぁ はぁ はぁ… ああ～～‼))
((うっ))
Mama?
((はははっ ははっ))
ふふふっ ふふふっ))
Mama!
((≫(ｴﾙ)ママ！))
((エル))
El.
The wind is really blowing.
(ｴﾙ)((すごい風だね))
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((そうだな))
It is.
It won't blow our house away, will it,
Mom?
((お母さん おうち
飛ばされたりしないよね？))
That...
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((それは… どうだろうな))
(ｴﾙ)((ええ～！))
I wonder.
((≪カタン… ドサッ))
((あっ))
((はっ))
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((何があったのですか？))
(ｿﾌｨｴﾙ)((お前たちは…))
What has happened?
Who are you?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)
((私の名はジャンヌ･ダルク｡➡
My name is Jeanne D'Arc.
この子は息子のエルです))
This child is my son, El.
((はっ｡ 私に構うな))
You must leave me alone!
((ドカッ！))
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((くっ｡ 何者だ!?))
Who are you?
What are you--
Where is the woman?
(漆黒兵)((女はどこだ？))
El...
(ｶﾞﾌﾞﾘｴﾙ)((あっ))
((エル！ エル！))
El! El!
((はぁ はぁ…))
Jeanne D'Arc?
((ジャンヌ･ダルクか))
I had heard she was living in hiding
outside the city.
((郊外に隠れ住んでいることは
聞いていたが➡
まさか
子供をつくっていたとはな))
I am surprised to learn she's had a child.
((しかも 漆黒兵を無力化する力を
持つとは…))
If the child has the ability
to strip Onyx Soldiers of their power,
((人間との子ではあるまい))
then its father is surely not human.
((その子供 神に渡ると厄介だ))
It would be troublesome for us
if the child were to fall into the gods' hands.
(隊長)((逃走経路を封じ
王都内に追い込みました))
We have cut off all escape routes
and chased them into the city.
((捕らえるのも時間の問題かと))
It is only a matter of time before they are caught.
((生死は問わん｡
神に渡ることだけは阻止しろ))
Capture them dead or alive.
It doesn't matter as long as you keep them from heaven's
hands.
As you command.
(隊長)((御意))
-Have you found them?
-No.
(兵士)((いたか？))
(兵士)((いや))
There's no doubt that they ran to this area.
(兵士)((この辺りに
逃げ込んだのは間違いない｡➡
見つけしだい殺せとの命令だ))
(兵士)((了解))
Our orders are to kill them on sight.
Understood.
((≫(兵士)３方に分かれる))
Search in all directions.
Mom.
((ねえ お母さん))
((ん？ どうした？))
What is it?
((僕たちは どうして殺されるの？))
Why do they want to kill us?
(ｵﾙﾚｱﾝ兵)
((お前たちは向こうを捜せ))
You three take the alley!
Yes sir!
((あっ))
((ゴロゴロゴロ…(雷鳴)))
((バリバリバリッ(雷鳴)))
Mom, what's that?
(ｴﾙ)((お母さん あれ))
((≫バリバリバリッ))
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((見るな！))
Don't look!
(兵士)((この中を捜せ))
Search inside here.
(漆黒兵)((見つけしだい殺せ！))
Kill them on sight!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((くっ))
You must live,
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ･心の声)
≪生きてくれ エル≫
El.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)≪この先
どんなに つらいことがあっても➡
No matter how painful your life may become,
お前に
手を差し伸べてくれる者は➡
I promise someone will appear before you
to extend a helping hand.
必ず現れる｡➡
その者を信じ
絶対に生きてくれ！≫
You must trust this person,
and do whatever that must be done to live!
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)((くっ))
I found them!
It's okay, it's okay
I cast the usual spell
Stagnation, stagnation
My words and heart are at odds
Default
I've taken all the paint
And mixed up all the colors
Until you're left with me
So fragile
Yet strong
Close to overflowing
But not spilling
Because I'm incomplete
I won't amount to much
This is just a good luck charm
I'm not asking for your help
I was just clinging to you
Let's end it all today
I'm done living this pointless life
I've taken my last, pointless breath
To whom it may concern, see you and goodbye
I killed the person I was yesterday
A new morning is coming
そのあと
すぐに 私は捕まったが➡
I was captured immediately after,
and I still do not know what happened to El.
エルがどうなったかは
分からないままだ｡
ジャンヌさん
ひどい目に遭ったんですね！
That is just so horrible, Miss Jeanne!
エル君 かわいそうだよ～！
Poor little El!
≫きっと
ムガロちゃんは エル君ですよ！
I'm sure Mugaro is El!
≫あっ
でも それだと ムガロちゃんは➡
But then that means Mugaro is a boy...
≫男の子ってことですよね｡
I want to see El.
私は エルに会いたい｡
そして また 共に生きたい｡
I want to live together again.
それが きっと
ミカエル様のご意志だから｡
That must surely be what Lord Michael's wants.
Lord Michael?
≫ミカエル様？ 誰？ それ｡
エル君のお父さん？
Who's that? El's dad?
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)まずは
そのムガロという子に会いたい｡
First, I would like to meet this child, Mugaro.
≫脱走ですね！
So we need to escape!
(看守)
この監獄から脱獄した囚人は➡
No prisoner has ever been able to escape this prison.
いまだかつて いない｡
あっ…｡
You hear that?
ですって｡ 私たちが第１号ですね
ジャンヌさん｡
Looks like we're going to be the first,
Miss Jeanne!
Hey, Jeannie.
-You must be Azabel!
-It's not -bel; it's -zel!
Well then, Zell...
Next time on Rage of Bahamut: Virgin Soul,
"Declaration of War."
-We did it, Zell!
-It's Azazel! Get it right!
Baha Soul!!
Baha, Baha, Baha Soul!
Just watch, okay?